<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Node.js Mobile Blog</title>
        <link>https://nodejs-mobile.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Node.js Mobile Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reboot]]></title>
            <link>https://nodejs-mobile.github.io/blog/reboot</link>
            <guid>https://nodejs-mobile.github.io/blog/reboot</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Dear community,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Dear community,</p><p>Ever since <a href="https://www.janeasystems.com/blog/node-js-meets-ios/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Janea Systems released</a> a groundbreaking proof of Node.js running on iOS in 2017, Node.js Mobile has grown steadily and is now a core component of several apps in production, on the app stores. I myself have been a core user since the beginning, when I dropped my own project <a href="https://github.com/staltz/react-native-node" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">react-native-node</a> in favor of Node.js Mobile.</p><p>Today, I continue to see more and more developers choose Node.js Mobile for their tech stack. Some may call this a big hack, but the reality is that this toolkit allows unparalleled code sharing on various platforms. Since Electron also supports Node.js APIs, it is possible to have the same background JavaScript code running on MacOS, Windows, Linux, Android, and iOS. If you also use the same frontend framework such as React Native (and React Native web), the same code sharing benefits apply there too. This is massive for developer productivity, whereas previously you had to use <em>five separate</em> native SDKs for each of these five platforms.</p><p>As the current maintainer of Node.js Mobile, I want to help keep this amazing project alive. As such, Autumn 2023 marks a reboot of Node.js Mobile, with the following four milestones:</p><ul><li><a href="https://nodejs-mobile.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">New docs website</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/orgs/nodejs-mobile/discussions/52" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">New version v18.17.1 released</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/nodejs-mobile/prebuild-for-nodejs-mobile" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">New official prebuild CLI</a></li><li><a href="https://github.com/orgs/nodejs-mobile/discussions/42" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">New donation system</a></li></ul><p>Going forwards, there is a lot more we aspire to add, but the most important is keeping this project well-maintained, which means cleaning up outstanding bugs and crashes, taking security issues seriously and urgently, catching up with upstream Node.js and React Native, and closely matching our docs with our source code. These are the basics you can expect. For that, <a href="https://opencollective.com/nodejs-mobile" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">donations</a> are vital fuel, so that's a great way how you can contribute too.</p><p>On the Cordova side, we are on the outlook for a maintainer to dedicate to <a href="https://github.com/nodejs-mobile/nodejs-mobile-cordova" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">nodejs-mobile-cordova</a>. If you are experienced in Cordova and believe you can maintain it, please <a href="https://github.com/orgs/nodejs-mobile/discussions/14" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">show up in this discussion</a>.</p><p>Thank you for co-investing in this tech stack, and together let's show the world how Node.js makes sense on mobile too!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>community</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>